Guide to the Steven Meretzky papers relating to computer game design and interactive fiction history, 1978-2009 M1730
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
- Series 5: Born-digital Materials
  Series 5. Born-digital Materials: This series consists of backups on computer discs, including saved games from Simcity Mac 1.1 1989, audio from Boffo Games ( Hodj 'n' Podj, The Space Bar, etc.), different versions of Infocom games, and assorted game design documents. Note: This Series is CLOSED UNTIL PROCESSED.
  - Simcity Saved Games - Simcity Mac 1.1, 1989 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Dreamworld Design Doc (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Game Development and Server Backups (Various games) (Box 50)
  - Boffo Games Audio Backups (Hodj 'n' Podj, Space Bar, etc.) (Box 52)
  - Space Bar Game Assets (Box 51)
  - Infocom Game Versions, Personal Games, and Backups (Box 48)
- Series 6: Periodicals
  The Periodicals series contains three subseries. Subseries 1 contains issues from the Journal of Computer Game Design published between June 1987-August 1996. Subseries 2 contains issues from Questbusters: The Adventurer's Journal published between August 1991 and May 1996. Subseries 3 contains issues from the Compuer Game Developers Association Report published between 1994 and 1998.
  - Subseries 1: Journal of Computer Game Design
    - Journal of Computer Game Design, 1987-1996 (Box 35)
  - Subseries 2: Questbusters
    - Questbusters: The Adventurer's Journal (August 1991- May 1996) (Box 36)
  - Subseries 3: Computer Game Developers Association Report
    - Computer Game Developers Report, 1994 - Spring 1998 (Box 36)
- Series 7: Realia / Ephemera
  This series contains realia/ephemera related to game publisher Infocom, Inc.
  - Infocom Realia / Ephemera (Box 53)
  - Infocom Realia / Ephemera (Box 55)
- Series 8: Magnetic Tape Media
  This series contains magnetic tape media including audio and videotapes from the Game Developer's Conference, a videotape of the demos for the game The Space Bar, and audio cassette tapes containing audio from the games Leather Goddesses of Phobos 2, Hodj 'n' Podj, Reverse Alien, and The Space Bar.
  - Subseries 1: Visual Materials
    - Space Bar Videotape Demos (Box 50)
    - Humor in Computer Games, Computer Game Developer's Conference, April 1997 (Box 50)
  - Subseries 2: Audio Materials
    - Audio cassette tapes with audio for LGOP2, Hodj 'n' Podj, Reverse Alien and The Space Bar (Box 50)
    - Game Developer's Conference Audio Proceedings
- Series 9: Photographic Scans of Selected Documents, 1426.0 gigabyte(s) 2 internal hard drives, 11,781 files [Extent on reading room media cart after filters applied: 30.8 GB, 6,286 files)
  Series 9. Photographic Scans of Selected Documents: Hard drives were given to Stanford University by Jason Scott, who scanned materials in the Steven Meretzky papers (M1730) before they were donated to the Stanford University Libraries. Jason described the materials that Meretzky provided to him as a "collection of influential writings and behind the scenes artifacts that a serious student of games and self-proposed archive of gaming materials would have to acknowledge as a world-class library." (Source: Jason Scott's weblog, (http://ascii.textfiles.com/archives/1357) The scanned items provide background on both business practice and game development at Infocom, Activision, and other companies for which Steve Meretzky worked during his illustrious career as a game designer.
  - AMFV (A Mind Forever Voyaging)
  - HHGTG (Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy)
  - INFOCOM CABINET
  - INFOCOM REUNION CD
  - LGOP (Leather Goddesses of Phobos)
  - MISCELLANEOUS SCANS
  - PLANETFALL
  - SORCERER
  - STATIONFALL
  - ZORKZERO